#### Contact

admin@vaclavkosar.com

www.linkedin.com/in/vaclavkosar-47755863 (LinkedIn) vaclavkosar.com (Blog) github.com/vackosar (Portfolio)

## Top Skills

Java Enterprise Edition SQL

JBoss Application Server

## Languages

Spanish (Elementary)

English (Professional Working)

Czech (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

**FCE** 

Scala Programming for Data Science - Level 1

Big Data Analysis with Scala and Spark

Functional Programming Principles in Scala

Spark - Level 2

# Vaclav Kosar

Senior Software Developer (AVP) at Barclays Investment Bank Prague, The Capital, Czech Republic

## Summary

Senior software developer with 5 years of experience and passion for Machine Learning on Big Data.

I love understanding and solving the business problems and learning new practical skills. I have passion for seeing robust solutions finally at work.

Blog: https://vaclavkosar.com

Mail: admin@vaclavkosar.com

Github: https://github.com/vackosar

# Experience

Barclays Investment Bank Senior Software Developer (AVP) February 2018 - Present

Prague, The Capital, Czech Republic

Big Data R&D Team focused on Spark and Hadoop.

Spark, Scala, TypeScript, ArangoDB, graph db, data lineage

Barclays Investment Bank

3 years 10 months

Senior Software Developer (Assistant Vice President)

September 2016 - Present

Prague, The Capital, Czech Republic

Latitude Project

Micro-service JMS messaging platform with web UI for monitoring, reporting and managing liquidity and credit obligations that allows the firm to significantly reduce costs and meet regulatory requirements for Basel III.

Agile Scrum, Angular 2, TypeScript, Docker, OpenShift v3, Spring Framework, Spring Integration, Solace JMS, SQL, Git, Maven, JBehave, Teamcity

Software Developer (Analyst)
May 2015 - August 2016 (1 year 4 months)
Prague, The Capital, Czech Republic

Latitude Project

Micro-service JMS messaging platform with web UI for monitoring, reporting and managing liquidity and credit obligations that allows the firm to significantly reduce costs and meet regulatory requirements for Basel III.

Agile Scrum, Angular 2, TypeScript, Docker, OpenShift v3, Spring Framework, Spring Integration, Solace JMS, SQL, Git, Maven, JBehave, Teamcity

Physter Technology, a.s. Junior Software Developer March 2013 - May 2015 (2 years 3 months)

Projects participated and skills earned as an Junior Software Developer @ Physter.com since March 2013:

Enhancements of Resource Management System O2.cz:

- EJB 2.1. Remoting. JBoss EAP 6.1. IA, SeSp, DD. Db migration for O2.cz: PL/SQL Developer. SQL Developer. jMeter.

Enhancements of a middleware:

- PGAdmin. Webservice, SOAP. Java EE. CDI.

Migration from JBoss 4.0 to JBoss 7.2:

- EJB 2.1. CMP. EJB 3. Hybernate.

Enhancements and bug fixes of a casflow prediction app:

- Tomcat. Spring. Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio Express.

Tools and utils:

- Posix shell (bash). Ant. Eclipse. CVS. Jenkins. SOAP UI.

Univesity of Montreal
PhD student
September 2012 - January 2013 (5 months)

PhD student for one semester. Then canceled studies.

## Education

Czech Technical University in Prague
Master's degree, Mathematical Physics · (2010 - 2012)

Czech Technical University in Prague

Bachelor's degree, Experimental Nuclear Physics · (2007 - 2010)

SPŠST Panská, Prague maturita, Digital telecommunication engineering · (2003 - 2007)

Université de Montréal